export const GOVERNMENTA2015 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The most visible feature of a state is",
A: "compulsory membership",
B: "defined geographical territory",
C: "written constitution",
D: "sovereign power",
answer: "B. defined geographical territory",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Representative democracy is characterized by",
A: "free election and proper register of voters",
B: "a politically educated elite",
C: "representation of the poor only",
D: "rule of the interest groups",
answer: "A. free election and proper register of voters",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The set of attitudes and beliefs that determine the behaviour of citizens in a political system is called",
A: "socialization",
B: "political culture",
C: "representative government",
D: "devolution",
answer: "B. political culture",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The set of attitudes and beliefs that determine the behaviour of citizens in a political system is called",
A: "socialization",
B: "political culture",
C: "representative government",
D: "devolution",
answer: "B. political culture",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Fundamental Human Rights are entrenched in constitutions purposely to",
A: "ensure freedom of speech",
B: "guarantee the liberty of citizens",
C: "promote good governance",
D: "promote trade",
answer: "B. guarantee the liberty of citizens",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Diplomatic and parliamentary immunities put limitations on",
A: "the rule of law",
B: "separation of powers",
C: "checks and balances",
D: "foreign policies",
answer: "A. the rule of law",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Montesquieu’s political theory of separation of powers was meant to",
A: "promote unity in government",
B: "prevent dictatorial rule",
C: "ensure social justice",
D: "enhance state security",
answer: "B. prevent dictatorial rule",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following countries practices a centralized system of government?",
A: "Nigeria",
B: "Ghana",
C: "USA",
D: "India",
answer: "B. Ghana",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following countries operates unwritten constitution?",
A: "Britain",
B: "USA",
C: "Japan",
D: "Canada",
answer: "A. Britain",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. A constitution that can be amended through ordinary law making process is said to be",
A: "written",
B: "unwritten",
C: "rigid",
D: "flexible",
answer: "D. flexible",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following systems of government operates on the checks and balances?",
A: "Theocracy",
B: "Presidential",
C: "Parliamentary",
D: "Monarchical",
answer: "B. Presidential",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Confederal systems of government means",
A: "powerful centre and weak component units",
B: "weak centre and powerful component units",
C: "powerful centre and powerful component units",
D: "weak component units and weak centre",
answer: "B. weak centre and powerful component units",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. In a federal system of government, the power shared between the Centre and state governments is known as",
A: "legislative power",
B: "exclusive power",
C: "concurrent power",
D: "judicial power",
answer: "C. concurrent power",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The prerogative power resides with the",
A: "ombudsman",
B: "executive",
C: "national assembly",
D: "civil organization",
answer: "B. executive",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Quick decision making is an advantage of",
A: "unicameralism",
B: "constitutionalism",
C: "federalism",
D: "republicanism",
answer: "A. unicameralism",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The organ of government responsible for the implementation of policies in a state is the",
A: "legislature",
B: "judiciary",
C: "executive",
D: "public bureau",
answer: "C. executive",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A citizen is an individual who",
A: "has the legal and political rights in a country",
B: "has lived in a country for sometime",
C: "enjoys only economic rights",
D: "enjoys immunity in the country",
answer: "A. has the legal and political rights in a country",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of the following is a condition for granting citizenship to a foreigner?",
A: "Swearing an oath of allegiance",
B: "Possession of a university degree",
C: "A registered member of a political party",
D: "Possession of an international passport",
answer: "A. Swearing an oath of allegiance",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Citizenship can be acquired through all of the following methods except",
A: "birth",
B: "nationalization",
C: "naturalization",
D: "marriage",
answer: "D. marriage",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The conferment of citizenship on a distinguished personality of another country is called",
A: "citizenship by birth",
B: "honorary citizenship",
C: "adoption",
D: "citizenship by registration",
answer: "B. honorary citizenship",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The primary aim of any political party is to",
A: "pressurize the government",
B: "remain in the opposition",
C: "control the government",
D: "ensure fair play in business",
answer: "C. control the government",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. A manifesto can be defined as the",
A: "opportunity to form a political party",
B: "proposed programmes of a political party",
C: "policy of a political party in power",
D: "power to rule the masses",
answer: "B. proposed programmes of a political party",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the following exists in a one-party state?",
A: "Only the workers party is allowed to exist",
B: "Only the students’ party is allowed to exist",
C: "Elections to the legislature are held at the party’s conference",
D: "The ruling party is the only legal party",
answer: "D. The ruling party is the only legal party",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following party systems best represents all shades of opinions?",
A: "Multi-party",
B: "Two -party",
C: "One- party",
D: "Elite- party",
answer: "A. Multi-party",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The practice of multi – party system in West Africa tends to promote",
A: "sectionalism and factionalism",
B: "national integration",
C: "social discrimination",
D: "economic integration",
answer: "A. sectionalism and factionalism",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Franchise is the right to",
A: "express political views",
B: "control the government",
C: "vote and be voted for",
D: "ensure good governance",
answer: "C. vote and be voted for",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The following are the aims of an election except that",
A: "a group sticks on to power",
B: "there is accountability of the leaders",
C: "there is a smooth change of government",
D: "the people determine who rules",
answer: "A. a group sticks on to power",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Politics is practically demonstrated during",
A: "electioneering campaigns",
B: "parliamentary debates",
C: "formation of political parties",
D: "inter-party consultative meetings",
answer: "A. electioneering campaigns",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. An election held to fill a vacant post in the legislature due to the death or resignation of a member is called",
A: "run – off election",
B: "electoral college",
C: "bye – election",
D: "primary elections",
answer: "C. bye – election",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following is a function of pressure groups?",
A: "Represent and protect the rich",
B: "Protect the interest of government",
C: "Serve as avenue for political victimization",
D: "Provide forum for the ventilation of grievances",
answer: "A. Contesting election",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Public opinion is defined as the",
A: "aggregate views of the people",
B: "sentiments of opposition parties",
C: "consensus of the mass media",
D: "reaction of pressure groups",
answer: "D. opinion sampling",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Public opinion on the performance of a government is best measured by",
A: "military strength",
B: "general elections",
C: "the mass media",
D: "parliamentary debates",
answer: "B. general elections",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The method in which a group of people are interviewed on a specific political issue is called",
A: "referendum",
B: "individual speech",
C: "individual writing",
D: "opinion sampling",
answer: "D. opinion sampling",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The Civil Service is an administrative institution of",
A: "the executive arm of government",
B: "Public corporations",
C: "Para – military organization",
D: "a business enterprise",
answer: "A. the executive arm of government",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following is a feature of the civil service?",
A: "Disloloyalty",
B: "Impartiality",
C: "Political activism",
D: "Temporary tenure",
answer: "B. Impartiality",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The major source of local government revenue is",
A: "donations",
B: "income from investments",
C: "loans from finance institutions",
D: "grants from the central authority",
answer: "D. grants from the central authority",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. In the pre -colonial African political system, the functions of the kingmakers were performed by",
A: "Age grades",
B: "Woman",
C: "Council of elders",
D: "Special people",
answer: "C. Council of elders",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Colonialism is defined as the",
A: "struggle against foreign domination",
B: "political struggle for independence",
C: "economic dependence on developed nations",
D: "imposition of foreign rule on a territory",
answer: "D. imposition of foreign rule on a territory",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. ‘Casting vote’ was one of the ways the Governor in British West Africa controlled the",
A: "Colonial treasurer",
B: "Colonial secretary",
C: "Native authority",
D: "Legislative council",
answer: "D. Legislative council",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The French policy of assimilation was based on the assumption that African culture was",
A: "expensive",
B: "inferror",
C: "unpopular",
D: "superior",
answer: "B. inferror",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The administrative structure adopted in the French colonial territories was",
A: "more of a centralized administration",
B: "focused mainly on traditional rulers",
C: "favourable to the African age grades",
D: "for the development of African culture",
answer: "A. centralized administration",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The Pan -African Movements emerged as a result of",
A: "African cultural heritage",
B: "European racial domination",
C: "the formation of the African Union",
D: "the growth of socialism in Europe",
answer: "B. European racial domination",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Which of the following was the first print media used by nationalists to oppose colonialism in the British West Africa?",
A: "Daily News",
B: "Daily Times",
C: "West African pilot",
D: "Guardian newspaper",
answer: "C. West African pilot",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. One of the prominent West African nationalist leaders was",
A: "Kwane Nkrumah",
B: "Jomo Kenyatta",
C: "S. L. Akintola",
D: "Sekou Tource",
answer: "A. Kwane Nkrumah",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Which of the following cannot be altered by a military coup d’etat? The",
A: "constitution",
B: "legal system",
C: "legislature",
D: "state",
answer: "D. state",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Laws promulgated by a military government are called",
A: "bills",
B: "acts",
C: "decress",
D: "proclamations",
answer: "C. decress",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The origin of the Commonwealth of Nations can be traced to",
A: "colonial ties",
B: "world economic order",
C: "equality of states",
D: "sovereignty of states",
answer: "A. colonial ties",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The origin of the Commonwealth of Nations can be traced to",
A: "colonial ties",
B: "world economic order",
C: "equality of states",
D: "sovereignty of states",
answer: "A. colonial ties",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The first black African to hold the position of UN Secretary-General was",
A: "Salim Ahmed Salirn",
B: "Kofi Annan",
C: "Emeka Anyaoku",
D: "Nelson Mandela",
answer: "B. Kofi Annan",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The Secretary-General of the United Nations Organization (UNO) is appointed for a period of",
A: "there years",
B: "five years",
C: "Seven years",
D: "nine years",
answer: "B. five years",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]